Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - A balanced cut would look best., 1925; 1925.0009.Orr; Uncle Sam is sitting in a barber's chair. He points to his long hair where it is labeled "High Sur-taxes," and "Tax on low incomes." The barber standing behind him is labeled "The administration." He reaches for his scissors labeled "Income tax cut."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for unknown drawing on verso." (Oversize 6)
    - His busy season., 1925; 1925.0010.Orr; LaFollette" is racing from the "G.O.P. Pond" to the "Democratic Pond." The republican fishing pole is labeled "LaFollette Poll" and the democratic is labeled "LaFollette Presidential Poll." The bait that he carries is labeled "Radicalism" and "Votes." (Oversize 6)
    - The busy watchdog, 1925; 1925.0011.Orr; A dog labeled "The Law" is chewing on a large bone labeled "Bone Dry Question." As the dog is occupied, a burglar labeled "Crime Increase" crawls through a window of a house. In the background behind a fence are two criminals labeled "Murder" and "Theft" who are watching the scene."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by the Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 7)
    - The bunker builders., 1925; 1925.0012.Orr; A "Citizen" golfer at a "U.S. Course" carries his bag labeled "Limited knowledge of Law." As he looks out to survey the hole, the entire area is built up with bunkers. In the distance are two "Law Makers" building more bunkers. The "Citizen" says, "Wonder if they're tryin' to see how hard they can make it for me?"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Doodles on verso." (Oversize 7)
    - Back to solid ground while others wait to be rescued., 1925; 1925.0013.Orr; A man labeled "England" is crawling out of the ocean labeled "Debts" to a rocky shore labeled "Gold standard" and "Sound financial basis." In the distance is a boat labeled "Financial wreckage of Europe" that has hit a large rock labeled "The War" that was sticking out of the water." (Oversize 7)
    - The bulldoggers., 1925; 1925.0014.Orr; A bull labeled "France's postwar financial problems," is being grabbed by the horns by a man labeled "Painleve ministry." Thrown from the bull were "Herriot ministry,"Poincare ministry," and "Clemencea ministry." (Oversize 7)
    - The busy mother., 1925; 1925.0015.Orr; A mother labeled "France" sits in a room with three crying babies, a ringing phone labeled "Debts" and food burning on the stove labeled "Franco-German relations." One baby pulls her hair and is labeled "Riffs." A baby in a cradle crying is labeled "Syrian revolt." Another baby crying in a cradle is "France's interest in China." In the foreground is a cat whose tail was caught on the rocker of the cradle and is labeled "Bolshevik uprising."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Barred! "Don't feed the animals!", 1925; 1925.0016.Orr; Behind bars at a zoo are men. To the left are "Teachers of evolution - Not permitted to earn a living in Tennessee public schools," and to the right are "Old Russian Teachers - not permitted to work or to receive outside assistance." Standing outside the cages are two guards whose arms are entwined. The guard to the left is labeled "Tennessee legislature," and the guard to the right labeled "Red Russia."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 7)
    - The beast., 1925; 1925.0017.Orr; Cartoon in three panels: 1. An Asian man labeled "Pacifism" has his ponytail in the mouth of a large tiger that is chasing him that is labeled "War." The caption reads: You can't escape by running from it...." 2. A man in a military uniform labeled "Militarism" has his rifle with bayonet ready as he enters a cave labeled "War." The caption continues: ...It's dangerous to hunt it....." 3. Uncle Sam now stands with a rifle labeled "Preparedness" as the "war" tiger sulks away. The caption continues: Our safety lies in neither tempting nor seeking it."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Back to normalcy!, 1925; 1925.0018.Orr; An angry and vicious looking man with the head of the globe is labeled "The World." He cracks a whip on the back of a man labeled "U.S," regarding "Same old worldly struggles!!" and Christmas bills that are on the ground. In the background Santa Claus with a "Happy New Year" hat is getting knocked off."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Doodle on verso." (Oversize 7)
    - A bee on board., 1925; 1925.0019.Orr; A sailor aboard the deck of a "U.S. battleship" is trying to hit a small "Air Service" plane with his mop."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune"." (Oversize 7)
    - Bringing up re-enforcements., 1925; 1925.0020.Orr; In the left corner is a military officer labeled "General Revenge" who is holding a bloody sword and pointing to the distance marked "Europe." The silhouettes of naked toddlers fill the foreground. In the distant "Europe" is another military officer labeled "Fear" who raises his sword to naked toddlers labeled "Coming Generations." On the upper left is a hillside covered with gravestones and crosses and labeled "The Last War."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. (Oversize 7)
    - Better call in the doctor., 1925; 1925.0021.Orr; Uncle Sam labeled "The Farmer" is sitting in a chair and bending over holding his stomach in pain from "Financial Cramps!" Scattered around him are empty medicine bottles of "Farm Legislation,"Farm Laws," and "Gov't Help." Through the window labeled "Economic Specialist" can be seen a doctor carrying a medical bag labeled "Co-operative marketing" and holding a piece of paper labeled "Diet List - Diversification - Wheat - Oats - Corn - Barley - Hay - Hogs..... ."on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Backwater., 1925; 1925.0022.Orr; Waters labeled "Bribery,"Liquor,"Graft," and "Crime" have flooded buildings in the background. Underwater are buildings labeled "Legislatures," and "Disrespect for Gov't,"The Home,"Contimation of our courts," and "Corruption of our police." Empty bottles and barrels float in the water. Hammering braces to hold up the dam wall is a man labeled "Short sighted drys." The dam wall is labeled "Prohibition Law." The braces are labeled: Enforcement law,"Volsteadism," and "Enforcement Laws." The man says, "I'll dam this stream forever!"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Graft: the acquisition of gain (as money) in dishonest or questionable ways; illegal or unfair gain. Andrew Vostead was the author of The National Prohibition Act (also known as Volstead Act) that was passed by Congress in 1919. The law prohibited the manufacture, transportation and sale of beverages containing more than 0.5 percent alcohol. Consequences of the act was development of gangsterism and crime. The increase in criminal behavior caused public opinion to turn aginst prohibtion." (Oversize 7)
    - The Chicago clipper., 1925; 1925.0023.Orr; V.P. Dawes" is bursting through the doors of the "U.S. Senate" with a lawnmower labeled "Dawes' speech. Inside the room are men all with long beards labeled "Senate dignity" and "Rules" that are touching the floor and could possibly be caught in the lawnmower."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Come on down!, 1925; 1925.0024.Orr; -no date on cartoon but in with 1925 cartoons.; At the top of the stairs sitting at her dresser is a woman labeled "Income Tax." At the bottom of the stairs calling up to her is a man labeled "Everybody." He holds in his hand "Tickets to 'Better Times' Opera" and yells to her "WELL!" Through the window, a "Business Taxi" is waiting with it's clock "ticking" away."sketch for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 7)
    - The challenge., 1925; 1925.0025.Orr; In the background is the silhouettes or a city with it's large skyscrapers. The city is labeled "CHICAGO - The crime and murder capitol of America." Standing straddling the buildings is the large form of a criminal labeled "Crime" who is carrying a bag of "Loot" in one hand, and a pistol that has been fired in the other. Lying on the ground beneath him are dead policemen with a sign that says "Seven policemen shot in five days." In the foreground are the backs of "Police Dep't"City Official,"Judge," and "Juror" who stand by witnessing the scene."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 7)
    - The critic., 1925; 1925.0026.Orr; A man sits at his desk typing at a typewriter and types "Criticism of 'Babbitt,' The American Business Man." Around him in the room EVERYTHING is labeled as having been manufactured by Babbitt ."doodle on verso. In 1922, Sinclair Lewis published "Babbitt." This satirical novel is about George F. Babbitt, a middle-aged, middle-class businessman in an average Midwestern city. the name of the book identified an American type and added a new work to the American dictionary. Definition: a business or professional man who conforms unthinkingly to prevailing middle-class standards." (Oversize 7)
    - The criminal and the law., 1925; 1925.0027.Orr; The upper image is that of a criminal who has fired his pistol running away from a warrior with a sword labeled "Justice" and a shield labeled "The Law." The text reads: In the past the criminal sought safety by running from the law... " The bottom image shows a burglar with his fired pistol running towards a warrior with a broken sword of "Justice." Her shield now reads "Protection afforded by law - technicalities - habeas corpus abuses - delays - Pardons - stays - writs." Behind her stands "His Lawyer" holding an "Insanity Plea."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chic..." (Oversize 7)
    - The cry of those who would not listen., 1925; 1925.0028.Orr; Men labeled "Miners"Politicians" and "Operators" have fallen through a man hole in a street. The man hole is labeled "Hard Coal Strike," and they are yelling "Help!" From the window of the White House is Coolidge, who is sitting at a desk, and a man labeled "Public Opinion."Public Opinion" is looking out the window and pointing to the man hole as he says, "Let 'em get out of it the best way they can, Cal. Next time they'll watch their steps."sketches for unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 7)
    - Canvassing our situation., 1925; 1925.0029.Orr; An artist, "Chas. E. Hughes" is working on a canvas with "Red, white and blue" paint. His palette is labeled "Hughes' speech before American Bar Association." The painting is of a woman labeled "American Liberty" who is surrounded by lions in a coliseum. The lions are labeled "Law making mania,"Religious intolerance," and "Prohibitory laws." In the background is a Roman emperor labeled "Intolerance" who is giving the thumbs down signal."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by the Chica..." (Oversize 7)
    - Careful! Careful! Playing their game again., 1925; 1925.0030.Orr; Men are around a table playing cards. The table is labeled "The Diplomacy Game - Geneva munitions conference." To the left are two men labeled "Europe's master diplomats." They snicker as they look at the card hand and one says "Ps-st! Bring another barrel." At the other end of the table is "Theodore Burton - American Representative." Hanging on the wall are two pictures of "American Diplomats" that are walking away naked and clothed with a barrel. The picture to the right is of the "Versailles Peace Conference" and the one to the left is of the "Naval Disarmament Conference."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Careful! Careful!, 1925; 1925.0031.Orr; On a sidewalk, there are two people that are walking. In the center of the sidewalk is a man hole that is labeled "Wheat Pit." A man is carrying a basket of eggs labeled "Family savings," and a bundle labeled "Public." He is paying attention to a beautiful woman labeled "Gambling lure" that carries a purse of "Easy Money" and wears a hat with a dollar sign and shafts of wheat coming from it. The man is about to fall into the manhole since he isn't paying attention as the woman is signaling for him to follow her."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Completed without a blot., 1925; 1925.0032.Orr; A chair labeled "20 years of public service" is at a desk with a book laying across the top. The book has written in it: Chas E. Hughes Record - with highest esteem, Faithfully yours, Charles E. Hughes." An ink well labeled "Integrity" with a pen labeled "Honesty" rests on the desk. In the background is Uncle Sam with his hand on Chas. Hughes' shoulder."E. Hughes was appointed U.S. Secretary of State in 1921 by Warren G. Harding. He resigned in 1925. He was appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court in 1910. Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Corralling a jury is getting to be quite a chore., 1925; 1925.0033.Orr; A "Judge" has a rope labeled "Duty to State" and is about to lasso a "Citizen" that is running away. In the background men are penned in a corral with a large sign labeled "Jury Service - $3.00 per day - Confinement during trial - isolation from family & friends." In the background are "Bailiffs" and "Lawyers" that are also lassoing jurors."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - The cause of our next war., circa 1925; 1925.0034.Orr; no date on the cartoon; In the background are hills of money labeled America's Wealth." A man labeled "Idealist" has a large mallet over his head labeled "Pacifism,'" that is being used to break a large sword labeled "U.S. Defenses." In the foreground is the back of a man labeled "Potential enemy." He holds a sword labeled "The next war," and he looks over a fence to witness the scene."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.; Copyright, ...... by The Chicago Tribune." date torn off on corner of overlay" (Oversize 7)
    - Closing in on him., 1925; 1925.0035.Orr; A baseball player, "European Evasion," is running between two groups of ball players. A tossed ball in the air is labeled "Debt Demands." To the left trying to catch the ball is "U.S. Statesman,"Public Sentiment," and "U.S. Business." The ball players to the right who are running after "European evasion" are "Taxpayer,"The Press" and "Coolidge" who threw the ball."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - The drawback!, 1925; 1925.0036.Orr; A man labeled "Dearborn" is steering a sail boat labeled "Chicago." The sails are labeled "Commercial progress" and the winds blowing are "Our Trade Winds." A boy points "To World's Greatest City." A large anchor is attached to the boat and wedged in rocks. The anchor is labeled "Chicago politics," and the rocks holding it are labeled "Roads, "Traffic problems,"Subway needs," and "Bridges."overlay torn: ...Off.; Copyright, 1925, ...Chicago Tribune." Doodles on verso." (Oversize 7)
    - Driven into the home., 1925; 1925.0037.Orr; In the background is a "Public Drinking Place" that is shut down with boards covering the door and window that are labeled "Closed" and "18th Amendment." Standing at the corner is a policeman swinging his billy club and his badge is labeled "Volsteadism." Going from the bar to "The American Home" across the street is a set of footsteps. In the front yard of the home are empty and discarded liquor bottles with a sign in the yard "John Barleycorn."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay torn: ...ff,; copyright, 1925, .....ago Tribune." Verso also has writing: Driven into the home."Prohibition."Church"John Barleycorn" (Oversize 7)
    - Deeds of children ofttimes reflect upon the parent., 1925; 1925.0038.Orr; A group of three young boys, two that are labeled "Unprincipled Lawyer,"Crook Lawyer," are in a large mud puddle labeled "Unscrupulous practices." They are throwing mud balls to a "Justice" that is walking in the street. The scales have been knocked from her hand and she covers her face as she moves away. To the left is a man the boy's father who is labeled "Legal Profession." He is holding his chin thinking as another man "Public" says to him, "Why don't you stop this disgrace? Folks will soon be thinking that you approve of it!"sketches for cartoon on verso. "Crime Wave" Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - The debt question., 1925; 1925.0039.Orr; Caillaux is walking in a "U.S. Field of Finance" scattering money labeled "Debt Payments" that he has taken from a seed bag labeled "Caillaux debt mission" that he carries on his shoulder. In the distance is the dome of the capitol building and Uncle Sam smiling and saying "The benefits you reap will be in proportion to the amount you sow." In the upper right corner is a picture of the land filled with grain marked "Future loans," and "Loans" and the caption "Regrowth of French credit."Caillaux (1863-1944) served as a finance minister in the cabinets of Paul Painleve (1925) and Aristide Briand (1926), but after each appointment a hostile chamber of deputies forced his resignation. He was subsequently elected to the senate. Paper overlay: Reg., U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - The debt controversy., 1925; 1925.0040.Orr; A "European Statesman" and Uncle Sam labeled "U.S." are talking to one another. The Statesman looks at a painting and says, "Remember, we were partners in the War!" The picture shows troops flying different flags in battle. Uncle Sam motions to another painting and says, " - But not in peace!" The painting that he points to is labeled "Peace of Versailles" and shows soldiers in a room full of money labeled "Territory,"Reparations," and "Spoils of War." The soldiers say, "Lock the Door! " and "Give him Armenia!" At the door is the shadow of Uncle Sam."for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Driving away her customers., 1925; 1925.0041.Orr; A woman labeled "Europe" is outside her home labeled "Board & Room." She is shoving her "War Dog" into a dog house labeled "Peace Guarantee," and says, "Get in there and quit growling!" On the ground next to her are nails, a hammer, and a board that says "Security Pact." Walking out on the street past the front gate to the home is a woman labeled "American Dollar" carrying a suitcase labeled "Loans."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: ..S. Pat Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Driven to drink - before and after prohibition., 1925; 1925.0042.Orr; Cartoon in three panels: 1. A bartender behind a bar says to a man labeled "Majority of Americans,"Have a drink?" The man replies, "Nope! I seldom touch it, Mac!" Running through the door is a man labeled "Drys," carrying an umbrella. A sign behind the bar reads "Aged Bourbon $2.60 per quart." 2. "Drys" grabs the man and says "STOP!! YOU CAN'T DRINK!!" His umbrella is labeled "Prohibition Law." 3. "Drys is now on the left sitting down all beat up with a black eye and bandages and the man says to the bartender, "Give me another bottle, Mac!" The bartender says, "Yes, Sir! Comin' up!" as he changes the sign behind the bar to read, "Green Whiskey 'cut' $6.00 per pint."for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Digging bait., 1925; 1925.0043.Orr; A man labeled "Debtor nation" is on the shore of "Europe" and digging for worms that are in the shape of dollar bills. An open can labeled "Debt Repayment" sits by a fishing pole. Out in the water is a bobber with an empty hook. Swimming in the water is a large fish labeled "More U.S. Loans," that is in the shape of a money bag."overlay: Re. U.S. Pat. Off.: Copyright: 1925: By The chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - The danger of too much economy., 1925; 1925.0044.Orr; Two U.S. men in military uniforms stand defending barrels of money, and a bag of money that is labeled "Happiness." A sign by them reads "Adequate defense." To the left, in the background is a large mound of money labeled "Prosperity" with a sign that says "America's wealth." To the right in the background is a man labeled "Congressman" holding a a paper that says "Economy program." He stands next to "Pacifist" who says to him as he points to the soldiers, "They're an awful expense! Why not discharge them?"doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.: Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Don't you remember way last fall - ?, 1925; 1925.0045.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: 1. Uncle Sam is a waiter taking "Political Orders" from a man, "Voter," who holds a menu that reads, "The Ballot - Menu - Congressmen - Senators...." The scene is labeled "Nov. 4th." 2. Uncle Sam brings a large dish in the shape of the capitol dome labeled "Political Orders," and "The inauguration."Voter," replies "O, Yes! I remember now. I did order something, Didn't I?" Voter's hair has grown, he has already eaten, and a large spider web has formed behind him. The scene is labeled "Mar. 4th."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Enjoying the cut., 1925; 1925.0046.Orr; To the right and left are shown two "Rival Bakers" each slicing a loaf of bread. In the foreground is young boy labeled "Consume" who is eating a slice of bread and carrying a plate of bread slices labeled "Bread price cut." The boy says, "M -M-M-M, Boy!"doodle for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - The endless chase., 1925; 1925.0047.Orr; there is no date on cartoon and copyright paper overlay; A fox labeled "The Criminal" is running around in a circle formed by hollowed out logs. The logs are labeled "Political Pull,"Police corruption,"Jury Tampering,"Legal Technicalities,"Delays," and "Bail Evasion." Standing nearby is a frustrated police office holding a gun labeled "Law" that is propped up on his shoulder and a stick in his other hand."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyrigh......... by The chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - - Easy to lead, but hard to drive -", 1925; 1925.0048.Orr; A man labeled "Temperance Leadership," holds a rope labeled, "Economic and moral suasion." The rope was once attached to a horse, "U.S. Public Opinion" that has broken free and jumped a fence labeled "Wild Oats Field." To the right is a man dressed in pilgrim attire labeled "The Fanatics" who carries a large bat labeled "Prohibition by Force." He has just hit the horse causing it to break free and "Fanatics" says to Temperance,"He wasn't going fast enough to suit me!"overlay torn: ......right, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 7)
    - Erasing the line., 1925; 1925.0049.Orr; Autos with license plates from "Indiana,"Illinois,"Ohio," and "NY" are seen racing across the "The Old Dividing line between the north and the solid south." A sign that reads "Mason and Dixon Line" has been knocked over and next to it is a sign that reads "To Florida via Dixie."overlay: Re. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary doodles for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 7)